Guide to the Pettigrew Papers
Yale University Library
- General Correspondence Files, 1797-1865; Series I:; 4.59' (13 boxes)
  - Carlisle, Nicholas, 1771-1847. 16 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1825-46 (Box 2, Folder 97)
    About Carlisle's post as Secretary of the Society of Antiquaries and Pettigrew's works, including Bibliotheca Sussexiana and Medical Portrait Gallery. Later letters are mostly on Carlisle's health, a few mention the vindication of James Halliwell.
  - Carnarvon, Henry Howard Molyneux Herbert, 4th Earl of, 1831-1890. 10 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1859 Jul-Oct (Box 2, Folder 98)
    Letters discuss a meeting of the British Archaeological Association in Newbury.
  - Carnwath, Robert Alexander Dalzell, 9th Earl of, 1768-1839. 2 ALS and 1 AL to T. J. Pettigrew (Box 2, Folder 99)
  - Carysfort, Elizabeth (Grenville) Proby, Countess of, 1756-1842. AL to T. J. Pettigrew (Box 2, Folder 100)
    Proxy vote for the election of the Indigent Blind.
  - Carysfort, John Joshua Proby, 1st Earl of, 1751-1828. 7 ALS and 2 AL to [T. J. Pettigrew], 1800-18 (Box 2, Folder 101)
    One letter (6/15/00) refuses a request for an office as Personal Secretary to accompany Carysfort to Berlin. The other letters discuss Carysfort's affiliation with the Philosophical Society of London.
  - Cattermole, Richard, 1795-1858. 3 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1845-53 (Box 2, Folder 102)
  - Cavan, Frederick John William Lambart, 8th Earl of, 1815-1887. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1856 Jul 3 (Box 2, Folder 103)
    Declines an invitation to be a Vice-President of the British Archaeological Association.
  - Chalmers, Patrick, 1802-1854. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1850 Jun 9 (Box 3, Folder 104)
  - Chambers, William Frederick, 1786-1855. 2 ALS and 2 AL to T. J. Pettigrew, 1818-38 (Box 3, Folder 105)
  - Champion de Crespigny, Sir Claude, bart., 1734-1818. AL to T. J. Pettigrew, 1816 Oct 8 (Box 3, Folder 106)
  - Champion de Crespigny, Sir William, bart., 1765-1829. 1 ALS and 1 AL to T. J. Pettigrew, 1823, 1824 (Box 3, Folder 107)
    Declines to contribute to a charitable cause.
  - Charma, Antoine, 1801-1869. 3 ALS (in French) to T. J. Pettigrew, 1850-51 (Box 3, Folder 108)
    Introduces Gustave Dupont and discusses the Société des Antiquaires de Normandie.
  - Cherry, Henry Curtis. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1859 Aug 23 (Box 3, Folder 109)
    Discusses an unpublished work by Cherry.
  - Chichester, Henry Thomas Pelham, 7th Earl of, 1804-1886. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, [1860?] Jul 24 (Box 3, Folder 110)
  - Chichester, Sir John Palmer Bruce, bart. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 111)
  - Cholmondeley, Susan (Somerset) Cholmondeley, Marchioness, 1804-1886. AL to T. J. Pettigrew, 1835 Jun 22 (Box 3, Folder 112)
  - Cholmondeley, William Henry Hugh Cholmondeley, 3d Marquis, 1800-1884. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, [1846 or later] (Box 3, Folder 113)
  - Christmas, Henry, 1811-1868. ALS to T.J. Pettigrew, 1855 Mar 14 (Box 3, Folder 114)
  - Churston, John Buller-Yarde-Buller, 1st Baron, 1799-1871. 2 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1861 Mar, Nov (Box 3, Folder 115)
    Declines an invitation to subscribe to and preside over the British Archaeological Association.
  - Cimitile, Principe di. 39 ALS and 3 AL to T. J. Pettigrew., [1823]-44 (Box 3, Folder 116-119)
    About his health and travels. Hudson Gurney is frequently mentioned. Also contains a memo from a Dr. regarding treatment given to Cimitile for Sciatica and Rheumatism, and 1 AL in Italian to unidentified, regarding the purchase of a mirror.
  - Clanny, William Reid, 1776-1850. 5 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1829-49 (Box 3, Folder 120)
    One of the letters introduces Thomas Elliot Harrison.
  - Clark, Sir James, 1788-1870. ALS and AL to T. J. Pettigrew, 1832 Feb (Box 3, Folder 121)
    Clark comments that he has not written anything of importance.
  - Clarke, Sir Charles Mansfield, bart., 1782-1857. 5 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, [1836]-41 (Box 3, Folder 122)
    Several letters discuss certain difficulties surrounding the publication of Pettigrew's works.
  - Cleveland, Henry George Vane Powlett, 4th Duke of, 1803-1891. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1865 Aug 11 (Box 3, Folder 123)
  - Cleveland, Henry Vane, 2d Duke of, 1788-1864. ALS and AL to T. J. Pettigrew, 1860 Jan, Feb (Box 3, Folder 124)
    Letters discuss a meeting of, and a paper for the British Archaeological Association.
  - Clifford, Sir Augustus William James, bart., 1788-1877. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 125)
    Clifford accepts the post of Vice-President of the British Archaeological Association.
  - Clifford, Charles Clifford, 6th Baron, 1759-1831. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1823 Mar 14 (Box 3, Folder 126)
  - Clifford, Charles Hugh Clifford, 8th Baron, 1819-1880. 2 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1861 Apr, Nov (Box 3, Folder 127)
    Clifford offers to aid the British Archaeological Association but declines to become a subscriber.
  - Clint, Scipio, 1805-1839. AL to T. J. Pettigrew, 1833 Mar 9 (Box 3, Folder 128)
  - Close, Thomas, 1796-1881. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1852 Oct 27 (Box 3, Folder 129)
    Close accepts an invitation to join the British Archaeological Assn.
  - Clot, Antoine-barthélemy, 1793-1868. AL (in French) to T. J. Pettigrew and 1 calling card., 1833 Jan 21 (Box 3, Folder 130)
    AKA Chevalier Clot-Bey.
  - Clutterbuck, Henry, 1767-1856. 8 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1818-41 (Box 3, Folder 131)
    Discuss the Medical Society and Clutterbuck's intention to run for the position of President.
  - Cockburn, Sir William Sarsfield Rossiter, bart., 1796-1858. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1856 Oct 14 (Box 4, Folder 132)
    Declines to join the British Archaeological Association.
  - Colborne, Nicholas William Ridley-Colborne, 1st Baron, 1779-1854. 5 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, [ca. 1849] (Box 4, Folder 133)
    Letters discuss Robert Vernon.
  - Coleridge, Sir John Taylor, 1790-1876. 2 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1861 Mar, Nov (Box 4, Folder 134)
    Declines invitation to become an associate of the British Archaeological Association, claiming he would be "neither useful nor ornamental" and noting that he is "not fond of any public performance."
  - Collier, John Payne, 1789-1883. 2 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1854, 1855 (Box 4, Folder 135)
  - Collyer, William Bengo, 1782-1854. 3 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1816-23 (Box 4, Folder 136)
  - Combe, Taylor, 1774-1826. 2 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1821, 1824 (Box 4, Folder 137)
  - Conolly, John, 1794-1866. 7 ALS and 3 AL to T. J. Pettigrew, [1829]-57 (Box 4, Folder 138)
    Discusses Pettigrew's Medical Portrait Gallery. One letter asks Pettigrew to support Conolly in his attempt to become a member of the Athenaeum.
  - Conybeare, William Daniel, 1787-1857. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1854 Jul 28 (Box 4, Folder 139)
    Accepts position of Vice-President in the British Archaeological Assn.
  - Conyngham, Henry Conyngham, 1st Marquess, 1766-1832. 2 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1831 Oct (Box 4, Folder 140)
  - Cooke, John, 1756-1838. 7 ALS and 1 fragment to T. J. Pettigrew, 1 ALS to unidentified "Madam.", [1829-32] (Box 4, Folder 141)
    One of the letters contains a long discussion of "Mr. Butler's 2nd vol.", presumably Charles Butler's Reminiscences.
  - Cooper, Sir Astley Paston, bart., 1768-1841. 14 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew and 1 ALS from Pettigrew to Cooper, 1815-38 (Box 4, Folder 142)
    At Pettigrew's request, Cooper recounts an anecdote about a "Mr. Belcher [James?]."
  - Copeland, Thomas, 1781-1855. 5 ALS and 1 AL to T. J. Pettigrew, [1822 or later] (Box 4, Folder 143)
    Agrees to subscribe to one of Pettigrew's works.
  - Copland, James, 1791-1870. 3 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1830 Feb (Box 4, Folder 144)
  - Corblet, Louis-Achille-Jules, 1819-1886. ALS (in French) to T. J. Pettigrew, 1857 Feb 20 (Box 4, Folder 145)
    Announces the gift of a copy of the Revue de l'art chretien, which Corblet hopes Pettigrew will publicize. Letter also states the goals of that publication.
  - Corner, George Richard, 1801-1863. 5 ALS and 1 AL to T. J. Pettigrew, 1845-52 (Box 4, Folder 146)
    Discuss Pettigrew's dispute with the Society of Antiquaries, which prompted his temporary resignation from that organization.
  - Cory, Isaac Preston, 1802-1842. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 147)
  - Costa, Sir Michael, 1810-1884. 7 ALS in French and 5 ALS in English to T. J. Pettigrew, 1840-50 (Box 4, Folder 148)
    Several letters thank Pettigrew for some of his works. Mentions that Costa is working on a new opera.
  - Costello, Dudley, 1803-1865. 5 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, [1856]-59 (Box 4, Folder 149)
    Discusses the British Archaeological Association, to which Costello belonged, and a monograph by Pettigrew.
  - Cotton, Henry, 1789-1879. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1851 May 9 (Box 4, Folder 150)
    Discusses his Fasti Ecclesiae Hibernicae and explains his methods and motives.
  - Coulson, William, 1802-1877. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1861 Nov 23 (Box 4, Folder 151)
  - Courtenay, Thomas Peregrine, 1782-1841. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1841 Feb 12 (Box 4, Folder 152)
  - Cowper, George Augustus Frederick, 6th Earl, 1806-1856. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1853 Jun 10 (Box 4, Folder 153)
    Cowper agrees to be a patron of the British Archaeological Association.
  - Coxe, Henry Octavius, 1811-1881. 2 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, [1846 or later] (Box 4, Folder 154)
    Letter discusses a drawing by Inigo Jones.
  - Craven, Louisa (Brunton) Craven, Countess of, 1785-1860. AL to T. J. Pettigrew, [1859 or later] (Box 4, Folder 155)
    On a trip by the British Archaeological Association.
  - Criticus, pseud. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 156)
    Reviews Pettigrew's Bibliotheca Sussexiana.
  - Croker, Thomas Crofton, 1798-1854. 4 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1844-46 (Box 4, Folder 157)
    On the history of the British Archaeological Association. Letters discuss Sidney Herbert, Edward Hincks, and Sir Thomas Deane. Several copies in Croker's hand of letters by Charles Roach Smith to TCC, TCC to the Marquis of Northampton, Northampton to TCC, and W. Brailsford to Northampton.
  - Cruikshank, George, 1792-1878. 5 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1854-55 (Box 4, Folder 158)
    Thanks him for the loan of 5 £. Sends condolences for the death of Mrs. Pettigrew. A third letter, written on a concert program, shows Cruikshank's support of teetotalism.
  - Cullimore, Isaac, 1791-1852. 4 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1838-44 (Box 4, Folder 159)
    Discusses Egyptian archaeology and Egyptologists in Great Britain in one letter.
  - Cunningham, Peter, 1816-1869. 2 LS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1852 Jan, Mar (Box 4, Folder 160)
    Two receipts for subscriptions to the Shakespeare Society, one for Sir John Swinburne.
  - Curtis, Sir William, bart., 1804-1870. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, [1859 or later] (Box 4, Folder 161)
    Accepts an invitation to become a Vice-President of the British Archaeological Association.
  - Darnley, John Stuart Bligh, 6th Earl of, 1827-1896. 6 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1853 Jan-Aug (Box 4, Folder 162)
    About the British Archaeological Association and a visit of the B.A.A. to Cobham Hall, Darnley's residence. Also about Darnley's refusal and later acceptance of the Vice-Presidency.
  - Dartmouth, William Legge, 4th Earl of, 1784-1853. 2 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1814, 1823 (Box 4, Folder 163)
  - Dartmouth, William Walter Legge, 5th Earl of, 1823-1891. 4 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1860 Feb-Oct (Box 4, Folder 164)
    About Dartmouth's contributions to the British Archaeological Assn.
  - Davidson, John, 1797-1836. 4 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, [after 1834] (Box 4, Folder 165)
  - Davis, Joseph Barnard, 1801-1881
    - 6 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1850-[56?] (Box 4, Folder 166)
      About Davis's entry into the British Archaeological Association and his attempts to obtain patronage and subscribers for his Cranis Britannica.
    - Prospectus (signed), n.d. (Box 4, Folder 167)
      Davis's Crania Britannica, including list of subscribers.
  - Davis, Nathan, 1812-1882. 2 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1835-52 (Box 4, Folder 168)
    Letters discuss Chinese bottles and corn found in mummy cases.
  - Delamere, Thomas Cholmondeley, 1st Baron, 1767-1855. AL to T. J. Pettigrew (Box 4, Folder 169)
    Withdraws membership from the British Archaeological Association.
  - Delille, Charles Jean. 2 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1834, 1841 (Box 4, Folder 170)
    Thanks Pettigrew for his introduction to Sir Sidney Smith.
  - De Morgan, Augustus, 1806-1871. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1845 Dec 17 (Box 4, Folder 171)
    About the Historical Society of Science, its collapse, and James Halliwell's role in it.
  - Denman, Thomas Denman, 1st Baron, 1779-1854. 4 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1838-41 (Box 4, Folder 172)
    Accepts invitations to subscribe to various works.
  - Devon, William Reginald Courtenay, 30th Earl of, 1807-1888. ALS and 2 AL to T. J. Pettigrew, 1861 Feb-Jul (Box 4, Folder 173)
    Declines Presidency of a British Archaeological congress in Exeter.
  - Devonshire, William Cavendish, 7th Duke of, 1808-1891. AL to T. J. Pettigrew, 1850 Jun 14 (Box 4, Folder 174)
    Declines Vice-Presidency of the British Archaeological Association.
  - Devonshire, William George Spencer Cavendish, 6th Duke of, 1790-1858. ALS and AL to T. J. Pettigrew, 1833, 1851 (Box 4, Folder 175)
  - D'Eyncourt, Charles Tennyson, 1784-1861. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1859 Mar 9 (Box 4, Folder 176)
  - Dillon, Sir William Henry, 1779-1857. 4 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1834 May (Box 4, Folder 177)
    About his attempts to gain command of a vessel or to be an aid to Sir Pultney Malcolm with the help of the Duke of Sussex.
  - Dimock, James Francis, 1810-1876. 3 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew and 1 ALS to "Mr. Archdeacon" (Box 4, Folder 178)
    About Dimock's work with the Church of Southwell, published in the British Archaeological Association Journal.
  - Dixon, William Hepworth, 1821-1879. ALS and AL to T. J. Pettigrew, 1854 Feb (Box 4, Folder 179)
  - Donkin, Sir Rufane Shaw, 1773-1841. 2 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, [1829], 1833 (Box 4, Folder 180)
    Declines an invitation to subscribe to a work of Pettigrew.
  - Donnelly, Sir Ross, 1761?-1840. 4 ALS and 3 AL to T. J. Pettigrew, 1826-33 (Box 4, Folder 181)
  - Dover, Georgiana (Cavendish) Agar-Ellis, Baroness, 1804-1860. AL to Mr. Stephenson (Box 4, Folder 182)
  - Downshire, Arthur Wills Blundell Sandys Trumbull Windsor Hill, 4th Marquis of, 1812-1868. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1859 Jul 18 (Box 4, Folder 183)
    Announces Downshire's willingness to help the British Archaeological Association.
  - Doyle, Sir Charles William, 1770-1842. AL to T. J. Pettigrew, 1823 Jun 8 (Box 4, Folder 184)
    Announces that he is prepared to act in behalf of a "Mr. Salisbury who was recommended by the Duke of Sussex.
  - Doyle, Sir John, bart., 1750?-1834. 2 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1829, 1830 (Box 4, Folder 185)
    Offers a "specimen of Indian antiquity" for the Duke of Sussex's museum.
  - Drury, Henry Joseph Thomas, 1778-1841. 3 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1829-32 (Box 4, Folder 186)
    Thanks the Duke of Sussex for any help he might have given Drury in obtaining the post of master of the lower school at Harrow.
  - Ducie, Henry John Reynolds-Moreton, 3d Earl of, 1827-1921. 5 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1860 Apr (Box 4, Folder 187)
    About Ducie's participation in the British Archaeological Association. One letter solicits funds from Pettigrew for the building of a church in Onslow Square (Pettigrew's address).
  - Duckett, Sir George, bart., 1777-1856. 2 AL to T. J. Pettigrew, 1830 May-Jun (Box 4, Folder 188)
  - Dufour, Charles, 1814-1887. ALS (in French) to T. J. Pettigrew, 1851 Mar 21 (Box 4, Folder 189)
    Offers the British Archaeological Association a commemorative medal struck by the Société des Antiquaires de Picaidie.
  - Dunbar, M. J. M. 7 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, [1853 or later] (Box 4, Folder 190)
    Letters discuss the Duchess of Hamilton.
  - Dundas, Sir James Whitley Deans, 1785-1862. 3 ALS and 1 AL to T. J. Pettigrew, 1829-[59] (Box 4, Folder 191)
  - Dungannon, Arthur Hill-Trevor, 3d Viscount, 1798-1862. AL to T. J. Pettigrew, 1860 May 14 (Box 4, Folder 192)
    Accepts Vice-Presidency of the British Archaeological Association.
  - Dunkin, Alfred John, 1812-1879. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1846 Jun 10 (Box 4, Folder 193)
    About archaeological matters dealing especially with Egyptian mummies and Druidic ruins.
  - Dunraven, Edward Richard Wyndham Wyndham-Quin, 3d Earl of, 1812-1871. 2 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1861 May (Box 4, Folder 194)
  - Dupont, Gustave Jules, 1820-1903. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1851 Sep 26 (Box 4, Folder 195)
    Acknowledges membership in the British Archaeological Association.
  - Dwarris, Sir Fortunatus William Lilley, 1786-1860. 2 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1857 Jul-Aug (Box 4, Folder 196)
  - Edwards, William Camden, 1777-1855. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, [1831 or later] (Box 5, Folder 197)
    Includes a prospectus for a numismatic work.
  - Effingham, Henry Howard, 2d Earl of, 1806-1889. 5 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1845-61 (Box 5, Folder 198)
    About a renewal of Pettigrew's lease and Effingham's connection to the British Archaeological Association.
  - Effingham, Kenneth Alexander Howard, 1st Earl of, 1767-1845. 3 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1843-44 (Box 5, Folder 199)
    About the rent and income tax pertaining to Pettigrew's residence on Savile Row.
  - Eglinton, Archibald William Montgomerie, 13th Earl of, 1812-1861. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1857 Sep 21 (Box 5, Folder 200)
  - Egmont, Bridget (Wynn) Perceval, Countess of, d. 1826. ALS and AL to T. J. Pettigrew, [1821 or later] (Box 5, Folder 201)
    Proxy vote for Pettigrew for the post of Surgeon in the Royal West London Infirmary.
  - Ellis, Sir Henry, 1777-1869. 14 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew and 1 ALS to F. Maurice, 1821-57 (Box 5, Folder 202)
    Letter of 10/21/30 mentions the unexpected resignation of the President of the Royal Society in favor of the Duke of Sussex.
  - Erksine, Thomas, 1788-1864. 4 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1856-60 (Box 5, Folder 203)
    About Erksine's membership in the British Archaeological Association.
  - Erksine, Thomas Erksine, 1st Baron, 1750-1823. 2 ALS and 2 AL to T. J. Pettigrew, 1815-18 (Box 5, Folder 204)
    About Erksine's admission into the Philosophical Society of London.
  - Essex, George Capel-Coningsby, 6th Earl of, 1757-1839. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1821 Jun 16 (Box 5, Folder 205)
  - Essex, Sarah (Bazett) Capel-Coningsby, Countess of, 1761-1838. ALS to Dr. Shearman, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 206)
    Authorization of a proxy vote in favor of Pettigrew's election as Surgeon to the Royal West London Infirmary.
  - Estcourt, Thomas Henry Sutton Sotheron, 1801-1876. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 207)
    Agrees to be a Vice President of the British Archaeological Association.
  - Ewart, William, 1798-1869. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1858 Jun 1 (Box 5, Folder 208)
    Announces his willingness to serve as a Vice President of a meeting of the British Archaeological Association and also to attend that meeting, if possible.
  - Exmouth, Edward Pellew, 3d Viscount, 1811-1876. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1861 Apr 22 (Box 5, Folder 209)
    Agrees to having his name associated with the British Archaeological Association, although he cannot attend.
  - Exmouth, Pownoll Bastard Pellew, 2d Viscount, 1786-1833. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1817 Mar 21 (Box 5, Folder 210)
  - Eyton, Robert William, 1815-1881. 3 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, [1856]-60 (Box 5, Folder 211)
    Discusses several papers written by Eyton.
  - Fairholt, Frederick William, 1814-1866. 2 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1852 May 29 (Box 5, Folder 212)
    About the Society of Antiquaries and Pettigrew's estrangement from it.
  - Falconer, Thomas, 1805-1882. 18 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1850-61 (Box 5, Folder 213)
    Writes about the problems of a circuit judge, his brother William, Pettigrew's works, a lawsuit by Pettigrew, and J. M. Traherne. Comments on the Crimean War and the American Civil War.
  - Falkener, Edward, 1814-1896. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 214)
    Discusses an article of his.
  - Farquhar, Mary Octavia (Somerset), lady, d. 1906. AL to T. J. Pettigrew, 1848 Mar 1 (Box 5, Folder 215)
    Discusses her help to a (presumably indigent) person.
  - Farre, John Richard, 1775-1862. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1831 Nov 5 (Box 5, Folder 216)
  - Faulkner, Sir Arthur Brooke, 1779-1845. 12 ALS and 2 AL to T. J. Pettigrew and 1 calling card, 1820-44 (Box 5, Folder 217)
    Mentions several of his works and travels; Sir J[ames?] Graham's Medical Bill; the Irish problem in Parliament, comparing the Duke of Wellington to Don Quixote.
  - Fellows, Sir Charles, 1799-1860. 2 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1855 Jul (Box 5, Folder 218)
  - Ferguson, Robert, 1799-1865. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1843 Aug 10 (Box 5, Folder 219)
    About a report by Ferguson on the education of Sir Charles Bell, which offended Pettigrew.
  - Ferrers, Washington Sewallis Shirley, 9th Earl of, 1822-1859. 2 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1851 May (Box 5, Folder 220)
    About his residence in the country and Pettigrew's son. Ferrers declines to become a Vice President of the British Archaeological Assn.
  - Ffolkes, Sir William John Henry Browne, bart., 1786-1860. AL to T. J. Pettigrew, 1833 Jul 19 (Box 5, Folder 221)
  - Filmer, Sir Edmund, bart., 1809-1857. 2 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1853 Mar, May (Box 5, Folder 222)
    Declines to be an officer of the British Archaeological Association.
  - Fitch, William Stevenson, 1793-1859. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1845 Sep 3 (Box 5, Folder 223)
    Mentions the rivalry between the British Archaeological Association and its competitors.
  - Fitzhardinge, William Fitzhardinge Berkeley, 1st Earl, 1786-1857. 2 ALS to C. Roach Smith, 1846 Jul (Box 5, Folder 224)
    Discusses a visit by the British Archaeological Association.
  - Forbes, Sir Charles Ferguson, 1779-1852. 2 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1817 Jun (Box 5, Folder 225)
    Agrees to introduce Pettigrew to Sir James McGrigor.
  - Forbes, Sir John, 1787-1861. 5 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1839-40 (Box 5, Folder 226)
    One letter discusses Pettigrew's Medical Portrait Gallery.
  - Forester, Thomas. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 227)
    About his translation of Ordericus Vitalis's Ecclesiastical History of England and Normandy.
  - Foster, Peter Le Neve, 1809-1879. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1854 Jan 17 (Box 5, Folder 228)
  - Freeman, Edward A., 1823-1892. 2 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1854, 1856 (Box 5, Folder 229)
  - French, Gilbert James, 1804-1866. 4 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1 ALS to J.R. Planché, and 1 ALS to [John E. Engan?] Secretary of the B.A.A., 1850-60 (Box 5, Folder 230)
    Discusses his admission to the British Archaeological Association and the Society of Antiquaries.
  - Fryer, Edward, 1761-1826. 2 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1818, 1828 (Box 5, Folder 231)
    About Pettigrew's affiliation with the Royal Humane Society.
  - Gage, Henry Hall Gage, 4th Viscount, 1791-1877. AL to T. J. Pettigrew, 1833 Aug 15 (Box 5, Folder 232)
  - Gardiner, Sir Robert William, 1781-1864. 3 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1848 Aug (Box 5, Folder 233)
    About his ailments.
  - Gerhard, E. ALS (in French) to T. J. Pettigrew, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 234)
    About an organization called Istituto di corrispondenza archaeologica; sends a section of the organization's by-laws.
  - Gilbert, Ashurst Turner, Bp. of Chichester, 1786-1870. ALS and AL to T. J. Pettigrew, 1854, 1861 (Box 5, Folder 235)
    Declines an offer to purchase one of Pettigrew's works and consents to the use of his name by the British Archaeological Association.
  - Godwin, George, 1815-1888. 2 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1853 Apr (Box 5, Folder 236)
    One letter seeks Pettigrew's aid in obtaining the position of Surveyor for Islington District.
  - Good, John Mason, 1764-1827. 2 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 1815, 1821 (Box 5, Folder 237)
    Turns down an invitation to be President of the Philosophical Society of London.